{
    "id": "ebab84393d8e4c8e8ec51dffeeb61f22",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "……………………. stringent antidrug laws, drug peddlers persist in selling narcotics.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition. It is followed by a noun.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "However",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. there are stringent antidrug laws, drug peddlers persist in selling narcotics.",
            "description": "Although is used to connect two contrasting ideas. It is a conjunction and is followed by a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "In spite of",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew no one at the party ……………………. that did not stop me from having a nice time.",
            "description": "But is used to connect two contrasting ideas. Note that although usually goes at the beginning of a clause whereas but usually goes after the first clause.",
            "answers": [
                "however",
                "although",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… my request for support, he did nothing.",
            "description": "In spite of is used to connect two contrasting ideas. It is a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "But",
                "Although",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I insist that the project ………………………… cancelled",
            "description": "Should is not normally used in the clause after insist.",
            "answers": [
                "be",
                "is",
                "should be"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I recommend that the highway ……………………… moved to another area.",
            "description": "Should is not normally used in the clause after insist.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "be",
                "should be"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He insisted …………………………. his attorney.",
            "description": "Insist is followed by on + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to see",
                "on seeing",
                "to seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. my childhood was peaceful, my adulthood is hectic and stressful.",
            "description": "While is used to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "As",
                "Since"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A huge tree now stands …………………………. I planted a small seed.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We started early ………………………… we wouldn’t get stuck in the traffic.",
            "description": "So that and in order that indicate the purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "in order that",
                "so that",
                "in order to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. his long legs, he is a good runner.",
            "description": "Due to is similar to because of.",
            "answers": [
                "Due to",
                "Although",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I always try new things ……………………………….. my fears.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "due to",
                "despite",
                "in spite"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}